The concept of value in factor modeling is one of the two most widely known concepts,
因子建模中的价值概念是两个最有名的概念之一
the other being the concept of momentum.
另一个概念是动量
The significance of value can be traced to the work of Ben Graham and David Dodd,
价值的重要性可以追溯到 Ben Graham 和 David Dodd 的著作中
who wrote about value investing,
他们讨论了价值投资
which seeks to estimate accompanies
即估算公司的内在价值
intrinsic value than by companies that are priced below that intrinsic value.
并寻找股价低于内在价值的公司
Some well known followers of Graham in
在价值投资领域追随 Graham 的
value investing are Warren Buffett and Charlie Munger.
知名人士包括 Warren Buffett 和 Charlie Munger
These types of investors are referred to as
这类投资者称为
fundamental investors are also discretionary investors.
基本面投资者 也称为全权委托投资者
Given the apparent success of value investing by discretionary investors,
鉴于全权委托投资者在价值投资方面取得巨大成功
quants have worked to replicate the idea by creating quantitative measures of value.
量化分析师一直致力于通过创建价值量化衡量方法来复制这些投资者的理念
Since I mentioned quants being inspired by discretionary investors,
既然提到量化分析师受到全权委托投资者的启发
I want to tell you about an idea I think is very misunderstood.
我就要说一个我认为大家误解很深的理念
This is something I am very passionate about, most quants,
我对这个理念很感兴趣
those who are new to quant
大多数量化分析师 尤其是量化金融新手
finance and even famous and very experienced quants often think and proclaim
甚至是经验丰富的知名量化分析师经常认为
loudly and even impolitely that
并且公开声称 甚至不太礼貌地声称
fundamental investors trade by gut instinct and have no process,
基本面投资者完全是凭感觉交易 没有什么标准流程
whereas quants are the standard bearers of
而量化分析师采用的是科学方法
the scientific method and they are the only ones with a repeatable process.
只有量化分析师采取的流程是可重复的
This is absolutely wrong,
这种说法完全不正确
I have worked with some of the best fundamental investors in the world in
我与全球最优秀的一些基本面投资者
addition to some of the best quants and both these groups,
以及一些最优秀的量化分析师都合作过
have had irrational well-articulated, repeatable process.
他们都具有合理 表述清晰 可重复的流程
The key difference though between the two are: one,
但是二者之间的关键区别是
the kind of inputs they use;
1. 使用的输入类型
two, how they process that information;
2. 处理信息的方式
and three, the shape of the portfolios that emerge.
3. 投资组合的形状
Historically, fundamental investors have relied on detective work together inputs.
以前 基本面投资者通过侦查工作来获取输入数据
This work includes reading corporate filings,
包括查看公司纳税申报
talking to research analysts,
与研究分析师沟通
and reading analyst reports.
阅读分析师报告
Let's think the company conference calls,
参与公司电话会议
talking to executives at the companies,
与公司高管沟通
and even visiting companies on-site.
甚至现场拜访公司
Fundamental investors then synthesize all this information into a variant view,
然后 基本面投资者根据所有这些信息得出不同的观点
which is a non-consensus view.
并非达成共识
The shape of portfolios differ between fundamental investors and quant investors.
基本面投资者和量化投资者的投资组合形状不一样
When I refer to shape,
形状是指
I mean the number of positions and also the concentration of those position.
头寸数量和头寸的集中情况
Think of the shape function in the Python library pandas.
思考下 Python 库 pandas 中的 shape 函数
Great fundamental investors have high IC,
伟大的基本面投资者
the measure of skill.
具有很高的 IC 技能
But, because of the style and depth of their research process,
但是因为他们的研究流程具有特殊的风格并且有深度
they can only achieve low breadth because it's only humanly
所以通常广度很低
possible to research so many companies with that much depth.
因为只有部分人能深入研究这么多的公司
But, make no mistake,
不过可以确定的是
these investors use repeatable inputs,
这些投资者会使用可重复的输入数据
follow a repeatable process and produce high IC bets.
遵循可重复的流程并产生很高的 IC 预测
Quants on the other hand,
另一方面
have historically used structured data like price and volume data,
量化分析师一直使用结构化数据 例如股价和成交量数据
financial statement data, quantified a research analyst ratings, and the like.
财务报表 量化研究分析师评分 等等
As discussed, quants typically have lower IC,
量化分析师通常具有更低的 IC
but more than make up for that with much higher breadth.
但是作为弥补 广度要高很多